[Episode 24]
Brother, you must remember the way home
and come back to see me often.
[Elder Brother Sheng's Grave]
Miss Yan lets us grow vegetables and fruits,
solely for Bofeng House.
Life is much easier now.
Don't worry about me anymore.
I'll be fine
on my own.
Brother, over there,
will you meet someone named Huang Bo?
He was about your age.
He was also a really good man.
If you meet,
you must take good care of each other.
Don't move.
I'm just listening to your heartbeat
to see if you're getting better.
Don't be shy.
My name is Luo.
I am a resident of Wangxian Valley.
What is your name?
My name is Huang Bo.
Huang Bo?
Miss Luo,
my gratitude cannot be spoken.
Thank you.
Is it not pretty?
I think it's very pretty.
This is the most special wreath
I've ever seen.
Does it look good?
It looks good.
[Gu Mansion]
Master.
You're here.
I came to see you and Madam.
She was so young.
Why did it have to be her?
Why?
Master, why was there an assassin
in your mansion?
It was not an assassin.
It was a thief.
That night, I heard a noise
and came out to check out.
But that thief drew a knife...
Ling Yi...
Ling Yi... Ling Yi took the knife for me.
My lord!
My lord,
the physician said Lady Yuan
had been pregnant for a month.
Master?
- My lord.
- What's wrong?
L-Ling Yi,
why didn't you tell me
that we had a child?
Had you stayed in the room that night,
nothing would have happened.
But now both you and our child are gone.
It's all my fault.
I failed to protect you.
I failed you.
I failed our child.
Master,
I know this is a heavy grief for you.
But the living will still remain.
Please do not let grief wear you down.
You are young.
You don't understand how painful it is
to live a whole life alone.
This journey... this journey is so hard.
Lord Gu, my condolences.
Lord Gu,
His Majesty understands how you feel
and sent me with a word.
He has granted you
a seven-day leave from court
to focus on your family.
Lady Yuan's passing was sudden.
Heaven's will is unpredictable.
If you need anything, just ask.
The imperial grace is vast.
I am endlessly grateful.
Zhi Li, let's leave for now.
Lord Gu's love for his wife was boundless.
Let them be alone for a while.
Master,
Lady Yuan's spirit in heaven
would not wish to see you so grief-stricken.
I take my leave now.
My child.
[Spirit Tablet of Lady Ling Yi,
Wife of the Chancellor]
[Censorate]
The imperial edict has arrived.
All of the officials in the Censorate,
heed the decree.
Since Meng Ting Hui
took charge of the Censorate,
she's been unfailingly diligent
and unwavering in her duties.
Profound in talent
and far-sighted in strategy,
she's repeatedly relieved me of my troubles.
She is truly my right hand.
Her efforts against evil and traitors
have been outstanding,
and her protection of me is beyond reproach.
I am deeply pleased
and commend her loyal valor.
She is hereby
appointed as Director of the Censorate
of the Senior Third Rank
with a twofold salary.
Predictions for the women's Provincial Exam!
Bidding starts at thirty taels.
Stop!
I've already worked so hard.
I've worked very hard.
In this world,
the shameless
live longer than the reckless.
The world is dark and murky,
and the night is endless.
Since the late Emperor
allowed women to become officials,
few female officials
have been able to serve a full term.
Women belong at home,
tending to their husbands and children.
An ominous star causing chaos,
and the reincarnation of a fox spirit!
The heavens are unkind,
and tears wet my robes.
I sign this pledge with blood.
If I fail the Palace Exam, I am willing
to be assigned to the Music Bureau.
Fierce winds and sudden rain,
what is there to fear?
I shall be the sword
that slays the fiends.
Execute!
Ting Hui.
- Meng.
- Miss Meng.
Miss Meng.
- Huiyuan Meng.
Meng.
- Zhuangyuan Meng.
- Miss Meng.
Zhuangyuan Meng.
Shen Zhi Li and Yin Qing are promoted
to be Left and Right Judges of the Censorate
with a twofold salary.
I trust that Meng Ting Hui,
Shen Zhi Li, and Yin Qing
will continue to uphold justice,
root out corruption, and safeguard the court
to share my burdens and serve the people.
I thank Your Majesty for your grace.
I've been fortunate to have you both
along the journey.
I should be grateful to have met you.
Without you,
I probably would've been
a routine Hanlin scholar my whole life.
Following you to handle cases,
I've witnessed many things
I never dared to imagine before.
I have never regretted joining the Censorate.
Wait.
Why still call her Miss Meng?
We should call her Director Meng.
Thank you, Director Meng, for taking me in.
I always said Director Meng
is a phoenix in hiding,
destined to soar high.
By following Director Meng,
not only can we feast on delicacies,
but even our official careers
advance step by step.
Wait a moment.
What position was I promoted to again?
Judge Yin.
To Director Meng.
To Judge Shen.
To Judge Yin.
[Censorate]
Although we have captured Ling Yun Fei,
we still need to find the person behind him.
Director Meng, the things are here.
I granted you all a day off.
Why are you still working on the case?
Greetings, Your Majesty.
Rise.
Does Your Majesty not know Director Meng?
The case is not yet closed.
So she doesn't care about rest days.
Your Majesty, what brings you
to the Censorate on this unexpected visit?
What? If there is nothing,
can I not come to see you...
See you all?
Your Majesty, don't misunderstand.
These things are not from the Censorate.
They're goods confiscated
from Wanxiang Pavilion and the Huxiao Gang.
I know.
With Director Meng here,
who would dare to embezzle?
We already checked these before
and found no issues.
We've decided to check them out again.
Anything unusual about it?
It is a Maojing pendant,
a tribute from Beijian.
There are only two of these.
My father bestowed them
upon the two chancellors.
If Ling Yun Fei truly
has a chancellor backing him,
then it is no wonder he acted so arrogantly.
It could never be Lord Gu.
Do you recognize this pendant?
You never saw Liu Ru Yan
in her final moments, did you?
Someone hit her repeatedly with a candlestick
until her skull was smashed.
When she died, her face was covered in blood,
spilling all over the floor.
Liu Ru Yan cherished her appearance,
but in the end,
not even her face was left intact.
Tell me,
what kind of hatred could be so deep
to do such a cruel thing?
Meng Ting Hui, shut up! Shut up!
Even before she died,
Liu Ru Yan was thinking of you.
She wanted to tell you
who exactly killed her.
During her desperate struggle,
she tore off this jade pendant
from the killer's body!
You recognize it?
There are only two of these Maojing pendants.
The late Emperor bestowed them
upon the two chancellors.
The killer
is either Xu Ting
- or Gu Qin.
- Impossible.
- Shut up!
- Ling Yun Fei!
Don't you understand yet?
He took out Liu Ru Yan
because I traced it to Liu Ru Yan.
He knew Liu Ru Yan was your most beloved,
yet he still killed her.
Because in his heart,
he has never been protecting you,
- Shut up!
- but himself!
Shut up! Shut up!
Say it!
Let's avenge Liu Ru Yan together!
Meng Ting Hui,
haven't you dreamed of killing me?
Do it!
He has never considered you.
Why do you stay silent
and protect him like this?
In his eyes, you are just a dog he kept!
Meng Ting Hui,
you're also just a mad dog
kept by the Emperor!
The Poisoned People's Mound killers this time
share the same moves
as those from the Blood Moon Society
who fought Zhi Shu.
And they deliberately avoided Meng Ting Hui.
Meng Ting Hui is undoubtedly
the Zhongwan princess.
Your Majesty also witnessed
the Blood Moon Society's attempt to kill you.
Have you ever thought
Meng Ting Hui's blocking the arrow that day
was just a ruse?
A spy from Zhongwan
has long been lurking by her side,
waiting to move.
Your concerns are not without reason.
But if it were as you say,
why would they force Meng Ting Hui
to take the Eternity Pill?
Your Majesty, Director Meng has sent words.
Ling Yun Fei has awakened.
He hasn't named his court contact yet,
but he's confessed the pharmacist
is from Blood Moon Society.
The Huxiao Gang and the Blood Moon Society
did make Eternity Pills together.
It seems my deduction is correct.
The Fuqing herb is a herb unique to Zhongwan
and contains a potent poison.
For safety's sake,
the Zhongwan royals took it
from childhood to be immune to all poisons.
Her body has already developed resistance.
That's why she wasn't seriously affected.
Meng Ting Hui has offered her own blood
to the imperial physicians
to make an antidote for Eternity Pills.
If they were colluding,
why would they leave such a flaw?
And why would Meng Ting Hui do this?
But while the Blood Moon Society remains,
Meng Ting Hui is a sharp blade
hanging by Your Majesty's side,
which could turn at any moment.
Your father had great foresight back then,
demoting the Zhongwan royals to slave status
and barring them from official positions
to prevent trouble before it occurs.
But Your Majesty has insisted on promoting
and placing great trust in their princess.
What you are gambling with
is the vast realm of the Ning Empire.
Father, Director Meng risked her life
to protect His Majesty.
She is unpredictable, and we must be wary.
If everyone were as naive as you,
where would all the blood and tears
in history come from?
Do you believe
that my father's decision
regarding Zhongwan was entirely correct?
What I want is not submissive subjects,
but the allegiance of all under heaven.
I sincerely
admire Your Majesty's vision and foresight.
But what worries me is Your Majesty's safety.
The Blood Moon Society
already knows Meng Ting Hui's identity,
yet they have allowed her to rise steadily
by Your Majesty's side,
becoming a key official of the Ning Empire.
They are surely brewing a plot
to restore their nation.
The Blood Moon Society lurks in the shadows,
watching with covetous eyes,
so I keep Meng Ting Hui close
to make sure they dare not strike.
Is this not also a form of balance?
Your Majesty, what about Huiyin House?
Take Di Nian
and search Huiyin House immediately.
Given the Blood Moon Society's cunning,
they've probably already fled.
But even so, you must investigate thoroughly.
As you command.
Chancellors, do you recognize what this is?
A Maojing pendant?
Your Majesty,
your father gave me
and Lord Xu each
a Maojing pendant from Beijian.
Then why is it in my hand?
Your Majesty,
- mine...
- Your Majesty,
I know my crime.
I carelessly lost it.
Where did you lose it?
I was careless
and cannot recall where I lost it.
I never thought Your Majesty would find it.
I am terrified.
So it's yours, Lord Xu.
Then where is yours, Lord Gu?
Your Majesty,
my late wife
hoped that I could be safe and well
all her life.
She treasured the imperial gifts above all
and always said the pendant
was a sign of your grace.
Even in her final moments,
she still held the pendant
and told me to always respect your grace.
I couldn't bear to let her go alone.
So, Your Majesty,
I ventured
to bury the Maojing pendant
along with my late wife, Ling Yi,
thinking that in this way,
she could still feel my companionship.
You have always been
deeply devoted to your wife.
I won't blame you.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Then, Lord Xu, you must keep it safe.
This Maojing pendant
was bestowed by my father.
If it is truly lost,
I am afraid you would have to pay
with your head.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I will certainly keep it carefully
and never lose it again.
With the Huxiao Gang destroyed,
the gang leader, Ling Yun Fei,
will be executed in public tomorrow.
I hope you two will supervise the execution
to uphold the law.
Yes.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I am a little tired.
You may take your leave now.
We take our leave.
Does Your Majesty believe
what the two chancellors just said?
Both chancellors are meticulous
and deeply calculating.
How could their depth be tested
with just a few words?
What is the situation with Ling Yun Fei?
With both coaxing and coercion,
Ling Yun Fei still refused to speak at all.
Since he won't talk,
we'll settle it at the execution ground.
I heard that Your Majesty
recently raided Huiyin House.
Situ Xue is a spy from Zhongwan,
and Huiyin House was where
the Blood Moon Society gathered information
and planned their moves in secret.
Situ Xue?
Zhongwan?
What's wrong?
A headache?
It's nothing.
Maybe I've been too tired lately.
I keep having very strange dreams.
Since they are dreams,
don't think about them anymore.
Tomorrow, I will take you to a quiet place.
From today on, it's yours.
This is Your Majesty's most beloved horse.
Are you truly willing to part with it?
Of course.
I have renamed it.
It's now named Qingyun Buzhui.
What does that mean?
May you soar to the highest heights
and never fall.
Your Majesty has promoted me
three ranks in a row,
and now you are giving me Qingyun Buzhui.
Are you not afraid
I will invite criticism again?
With you and me united in court,
any criticism or misunderstanding
is not worth worrying about.
For years, no female official in Ning Empire
has ever made a lasting mark in the court.
Not because women are incapable,
but because the world does not allow it.
Now, this horse can only be ridden by you.
Since Your Majesty says so,
I will accept Qingyun Buzhui.
When I first met you,
you were full of schemes and cunning words.
Later, you defied power
and never pandered to the throne.
You even dared to argue with me.
But it was precisely you
who showed me a resilience no one else has.
Meng Ting Hui,
I know how hard
your journey has been.
As an Emperor,
I am long accustomed
to weighing pros and cons
and to forbearance and restraint.
I originally thought
no one could shake my emotions.
But then you
suddenly barged in.
Meng Ting Hui,
I am fond of you.
For a ruler and his subject in love,
even a simple touch constitutes a crime.
Do you dare?
I am also fond of Your Majesty
more than yesterday
but slightly less than tomorrow.
I will make a trip to the Censorate
and silence him forever.
The Censorate is swarming
with the Divine Guard.
I'm afraid not even a fly can get in.
Today, His Majesty
used the Maojing pendant to test us.
I assume Ling Yun Fei already
knows about the death of Liu Ru Yan.
Lord Gu, what a rare guest.
Meng Ting Hui has traced the leads
to Wanxiang Pavilion.
Stop distributing the Eternity Pills
at Wanxiang Pavilion now.
You don't think Wanxiang Pavilion
is his only outlet, do you?
His business dealings
are not yours to control.
If Meng Ting Hui finds out the truth,
we will all have to go down with him.
That would be quite nice.
I will accompany him
on the way to the underworld.
He has grown increasingly insolent
over the years,
defying me time and again
and refusing to obey.
It's all instigated by you, you wretch.
I am a wretch?
Back then, when your father
was infatuated with his mother,
he didn't despise her
for being from a brothel.
Shut up!
If you insist on this,
this time, I will personally see to his end.
I have my own way to get out unscathed.
If you dare harm him,
even if I die,
I will drag you down too.
I will make the people see
the true face
of Ning Empire's virtuous chancellor.
A lowly brothel wretch dares to threaten me?
He's the one who made you chancellor.
Without him,
you are nothing
but a useless one in an official robe.
I killed Liu Ru Yan.
He will definitely betray me.
Whether he lives or dies
doesn't matter anymore.
You may leave.
I studied hard for ten years.
I had no powerful family
or imperial favor to rely on.
I climbed up step by step all by myself.
Who does Meng Ting Hui think she is?
She's just
riding on His Majesty's sordid desires.
And me?
I planned my every step carefully.
I've finally reached where I am now.
Now,
to think I'd be brought down
by a lowborn wretch.
Ling Yun Fei,
you were born to be my nemesis.
I should've let you
be beaten to death back then.
In the end,
you're dragging me down with you.
You win.
Ling Yun Fei,
you win.
You win.
[Spirit Tablet of Lady Ling Yi,
Wife of the Chancellor]
You laugh at me?
Even you laugh at me?
[Spirit Tablet of Lady Ling Yi,
Wife of the Chancellor]
What right do you have to laugh at me?
A lifetime of scheming
all comes to a broken end.
A name to go down in history
ultimately turns into a delusion.
Retribution.
It is all retribution!
Master!
Master,
the deceased are gone.
You must not do anything silly.
Madam would not have wanted to see you
tormenting yourself like this.
Master, everything will get better.
Master,
Madam would also want you to be well.
Everything will be fine.
They finally caught him.
Miss Meng truly
fulfilled the military pledge.
She caught the villain
and will have him publicly beheaded.
From now on,
we no longer need to live in fear.
- Right.
- Yes, Miss Meng is amazing!
- So impressive!
- Well done!
Miss Meng is formidable!
Kneel!
Miss Meng is so formidable!
Supervised by both chancellors,
what a grand display.
Even if I go to the underworld,
this is enough to boast about.
No wonder you have us supervise the execution
after you captured Ling Yun Fei.
So you just want us to see firsthand
how the commoners praise you.
You caught a bandit chief,
and you want to flaunt in front of me?
Miss Meng is amazing!
Miss Meng!
- Impressive!
- Well done!
Miss Meng is amazing.
Thanks to Miss Meng!
Ling Yun Fei,
your enemy
is sitting right up there.
He not only killed your beloved
but also wants to watch you die.
I know you hate him.
I came to give you one last chance.
Tell me who he is.
I will make him die with you.
Even offering a bowl of rice?
Still giving him food?
He still has to be given his last meal.
For such a vicious criminal,
you needn't trouble yourself
with the last meal.
Whether it is a person of great evil
or a person of outstanding merit,
they are all ordinary beings.
As I am the supervisor of execution,
it is my duty to be just and without bias.
Even when facing someone like Ling Yun Fei,
who is about to be executed,
we cannot lose the rules.
Lord Gu speaks with reason!
Well said!
Beat him!
With me here, who dares bully my brother?
Yun Fei, are you alright?
I'm your brother.
Come.
It's delicious.
Slow down.
Don't choke.
Brother, why aren't you eating?
I'm not hungry. You eat more.
This food tastes
just like it did twenty years ago.